A Guide to the George R. Talcott Papers
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
George R. Talcott Papers 1948-1981
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M 241
6 linear feet
George R. Talcott
Administrative Information
Access
No restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the Department by Mr. Talcott in September 1987. Accession number 87-Jun-34
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. Talcott served the city of Richmond for many years in the area of public utilities. He was also involved in the Annexation of Chesterfield in the 1970s.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of reports, studies and other government documents relating to Richmond, Virginia. Topics include public utilities, schools and integration, urbanization, and the Richmond annexation of Chesterfield and ensuing lawsuits. The bulk of the material covers the 1970s.
Arrangement
The arrangement is alphabetical except for the oversize materials which are filed separately
Contents List
- Annexation, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1.1)
- Annexation, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 1.2)
- Annexation--Chesterfield County, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 1.3)
- Annexation--Chesterfield County, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1.4)
- Annexation--Chesterfield County, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1.5)
- Annexation--Consolidation, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Annexation--Consolidation (Richmond), 1965-1973 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Annexation--Henrico County, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Annexation--Richmond, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Appraisal of Local Government in Virginia, 1973 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Bartholomew Report, Growth and Expansion of Richmond Urban Area, 1963 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Chesterfield, 1969
- Chesterfield County (Box-folder 3:1)
- City Planning Commission Reports (No. 1-7 of a series), 1975-1981 (Box-folder 3:2)
- City of Richmond Exhibits, Volume 1, Annexation Proceedings, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Clippings-Council, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Economic Development--City, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Economic Development--State, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Environment, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Federal--Judicial, 1980 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Finances--Richmond (Debt, Tax, Assessment), 1966-1970 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Five Years of Progress--A Report to the Citizens of Richmond, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Government (General)--Chesterfield County, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 4:7)
- Government--Services for Henrico County, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Hanover County, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Hanover County, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Housing, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Local Government, Other, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Metropolitan Areas Study, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 6:1)
- Metropolitan Areas Study (Hahn Commission), 1965-1969 (Box-folder 6:2)
- Metropolitan Areas Study (Hahn Commission), 1970-1974 (Box-folder 6:3)
- Miscellaneous, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 6:4)
- Petersburg Data, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 7:1)
- Plan for Government for the Richmond Reagan, 1969 (Box-folder 7:2)
- Planning Districts, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7:3)
- Richmond--General folder 1 and 2, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 7:4)
- Richmond--General folder 3 and 4, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 7:5)
- Richmond Government (general), 1973-1976 (Box-folder 8:1)
- Richmond--Holt, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 8:2)
- Richmond--Political, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 8:3)
- Richmond Regional Development Plan, 1967 (Box-folder 8:4)
- Richmond Reports, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 8:5)
- Schools--Integration EEO, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 9:1)
- Schools--Richmond, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 9:2)
- Schools--Richmond, 1972 (Box-folder 9:3)
- Sewers--Chesterfield County, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 9:4)
- Sewers--Henrico County, 1950-1967 (Box-folder 9:5)
- Sewage Facilities--Composite Reports, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 9:6)
- Sewage Facilities Report for NE Chesterfield County, 1957 (Box-folder 9:7)
- Sewage Facilities Reports, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 10:1)
- State Elections, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 10:2)
- State-Federal Grants (Urban 12), 1070-1971 (Box-folder 10:3)
- State--General, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 10:4)
- State Legistlation, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 10:5)
- Transportation, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 11:1)
- Unionism, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 11:2)
- Urbanization, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 11:3)
- Urbanization (State, Federal), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11:4)
- Welfare, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 11:5)
- Water Henrico County, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 11:6)
- Annexation, 1959-1979 (Box-folder 12:1)
- Capital City Government Commission, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12:2)
- Chesterfield Annexation and Voting Rights, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 12:3)
- City Responses to State Studies, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 12:4)
- City vs. USA, n.d. (Box-folder 12:5)
- Consolidation Effort, 1961 (Box-folder 12:6)
- Henrico Annexation Rejection, 1965 (Box-folder 12:7)
- Henrico County to a City (Box-folder 12:8)
- Local Governments, 1963-1984 (Box-folder 12:9)
- Richmond History, 1970-1985 (Box-folder 12:10)
- Revenue Sharing, 12:11 (Box-folder 12:11)
- State Financial Aid to Local Units, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 12:12)
- ACIR State Legislative Programs, 1975 (Box 13)
- Alternative Approaches to Governmental Reorganization in Metropolitan Areas, 1962 (Box 13)
- American Federalism, 1974; Oversize (Box 13)
- American Federalism, 1974; Oversize (Box 13)
- Annexation Proceedings--City of Richmond vs. County of Henrico, Oversize (Box 13)
- Blueprint for Improvement, 1966; Oversize (Box 13)
- Building the American City, n.d.; Oversize (Box 13)
- Chesterfield Exhibits, 1969; Oversize (Box 13)
- City of Richmond vs. County of Chesterfield, 1969; Oversize (Box 13)
- Conditions in 18 Large Metropolitan Areas, 1972; Oversize (Box 13)
- Edwards on Administration, 1967; Oversize (Box 13)
- Engineer and the City, 1969; Oversize (Box 13)
- Fiscal Prospects and Alternatives, 1971; Oversize (Box 13)
- Government Management Study, 1970; Oversize (Box 13)
- Growing and Declining Urban Areas, 1976; Oversize (Box 13)
- Hearings on Substate Regionalism, 1974; Oversize (Box 13)
- Holt vs. Richmond, 1971; Oversize (Box 13)
- Impact of Annexation on City Finances, 1973; Oversize (Box 14)
- Improving Urban America, 1976; Oversize (Box 14)
- Local Financial COncerns, 1976; Oversize (Box 14)
- Local Revenue Diversification, 1974; Oversize (Box 14)
- Measuring the Fiscal Blood Pressure, 1964-1975; Oversize (Box 14)
- Measuring the Fiscal Capacity and Efforts of State and Local Areas, 1971; Oversize (Box 14)
- Modernizing Local Government, 1966; Oversize (Box 14)
- Modernizing State Government, 1967; Oversize (Box 14)
- Planning and Urban Development, Oversize (Box 14)
- Pragmatic Federalism, 1976; Oversize (Box 14)
- Property Tax Circuit Breakers, 1975; Oversize (Box 14)
- Property Tax in a Changing Environment, 1974; Oversize (Box 14)
- Regionalism Revisited, 1977; Oversize (Box 14)
- Reshaping Government in Metropolitan Areas, 1970; Oversize (Box 14)
- Single Government, 1968; Oversize (Box 14)
- Staff Report to the Revenue Resources and Economic Study Commission, 1970; Oversize (Box 14)
- State Limitations on Local Taxes and Expenditures, 1977; Oversize (Box 14)
- State Mandating of Local Expenditures, 1978; Oversize (Box 14)
- The State of State-Local Revenue Sharing, 1980; Oversize (Box 14)
- Substate Regionalism and the Federal System, 1973; Oversize (Box 14)
- Survey of Urban Indicator Data, 1970-1977; Oversize (Box 14)
- Toward a more Effective Partnership, 1975; Oversize (Box 14)
- Trends in Metropolitan American, 1977; Oversize (Box 14)
- Value-added Tax and the Alternative Sources of Federal Revenue, 1973; Oversize (Box 14)